世界上有三种人
生者
死者
还有出海的人
——亚里士多德
叙利亚海岸 - 塔尔图斯港
这渔船上挺开心的
那是14号商船
保持低速
抱歉
我宁愿听听大海的声音
袜子侠，累了？
我叫尚特雷德
有信号进来
是潜水员的频率
（摩尔斯码）
U(Uniform)
U(Uniform) B(Bravo)
潜水员到位了
准备潜水
请求确认
- 副舰长？
- 收到
检查一下环境
附近商船 方位160
14号
- 1,000m，没问题？
- 确认
- 渔船，方位190.
- 100m，保持
- 没问题？
- 海面没问题
那是什么？
干！
护卫舰 方位150
它开始动了
护卫舰 方位151
发过来
保持8,000m，3节
航向350
- 跟住它
- 收到
袜子侠，你可以识别一下？
它发射“多项式”声纳
所以一定是无畏级驱逐舰（1155型反潜舰）
- 或者是改良版
- 所以是俄罗斯
等等，我听到它的螺旋桨了
气蚀空化
万马崩腾的声音
104转 数数叶片
七叶螺旋桨，不是俄罗斯
伊朗护卫舰
查拉图斯特拉号
伊朗军舰在叙利亚海域？
查拉图斯特拉号 很好的船
速度快，装备好
鱼雷，火箭发射，榴弹炮
还有吓人的声纳
保持警惕
绘图！
什么时候进入它的范围？
查拉图斯特拉号 方位154
一分钟
还有多久接到潜水员？
四分钟
在伊朗护卫舰旁边接他们
有点刺激
听好了
首要的是避免护卫舰反侦察
静音操作状态
穿上拖鞋，不要发出声音
从鱼雷管接潜水员
收到
D区，这里是控制室
清空3号和4号鱼雷管
鱼雷管灌水
内部锁紧
D区 收到
还有，静音很有用
我们要悄悄通过
问问Kiwi
不要再清扫D区了
声纳上会出噪音
D区，关掉吸尘器
吵到我们的金耳朵了
收到
还有啥？
哦还有厨房
这几个人早饭看这个
天性使然
至少船体没有振动
叫指挥官到控制室来
舰长，潜水员还有3分钟到
检测到了伊朗护卫舰
没有反侦察，但距离很近
3号和4号鱼雷管已经打开
确认去接他们
- 很好，确认
- 收到
看那条声痕
我什么都没听到
U(Uniform)
等等
海底的声音
- VTWA!
- 无音频视频追踪
重复 VTWA!
- 在5区
- 方位355
追踪它
好像有点动静
很弱，在快速移动
节奏很慢
一次四下
四叶螺旋桨，奇怪
- 货运船而已，我们没事
- 不
声痕很窄，是静音运行
肯定是潜艇
- 没有四叶螺旋桨的潜艇
- 我知道
等等，声痕里有短促的声音
快决断，这不是联合国开会
听到吗？
听到短促的声音了
但我觉得是生物发出的
- 抹香鲸？
- 生病了的
别捣糨糊
海豚还是潜艇？
潜水员他们，到底能不能去接
- 我在分析
- 快点
- 别吵了
- 声纳兵
精良的潜艇比大海还安静
是潜水员
R(Romeo) R(Romeo) U(Uniform)
收到紧急代码
- 他们很危险，快决断
- 听我指示
先等金耳朵听出来
长官，执行蓝色行动
我们离开，六小时后回来
快点分辨出来
那到底是什么？
快点，这不是演习
加油，袜子侠
四叶螺旋桨，不是潜艇
但这么安静不可能是货船
仔细听，尚特雷德
跟随直觉
我感觉什么都不是
- 只是另一头抹香鲸
- 等等
- 什么都不是
- 让我想想
未知信号
我相信你
好吧，不是潜艇
我辨认错了
没有潜艇，继续
- 确认去接潜水员
- 收到
收到，很快会接到潜水员
把抹香鲸和潜艇搞混
各就各位，还有一分钟
舰长，现在潜艇我控制
声纳兵，定位一下信号
方位040 他们从右面过来
收到，盯住信号
我们靠近查理2号点了
- 快！
- 右方15度，方位045
- 收到
沙滩右方15度，方位045
很好
当前航向045
- 很好
- 潜水员还有1,300m
五秒后3号发动机停车
- 快
- 3号发动机停车，速度降到200m
3号发动机调整完成
航速5节
4.8节，4.5...
干！
你的抹香鲸又来了？
短促的声音
它就在后面，不是货船
可能是潜艇，方位347
在左边，四叶螺旋桨
- 没有四叶的潜艇
- 我知道
注意方位347可能有潜艇！
五秒内给我查清楚
五秒内查清楚
安静！可能有潜艇
- 查出来了吗？
- 潜艇可能方位220
航速5节 距离3,000m
清楚了点
5.5节 距离2,900m
收到了
临时命名 塞拉
塞拉 收到
辨认潜艇，方位210
距离2,900 m 航速5.5节
听到螺旋桨了
有气蚀的声音
潜艇威胁等级2
方位346
辨认它的船型
别再搞砸了
它改变航向了
潜艇威胁等级3
指挥官，未知潜艇意味着要执行回显计划
我们得溜走
我们的任务是接潜水员
快点！
声纳兵，盯紧塞拉
- 准备一枚鱼雷
- 一号鱼雷管！
长官，螺旋桨转速70转，可能是中国人
四叶螺旋桨的中国潜艇？不可能
很难相信，可能是俄罗斯的美洲狮
- 美洲狮还没服役
- 我当然知道
对，四叶螺旋桨
肯定是新型的潜艇
刚才是抹香鲸，现在又来试水的美洲狮潜艇？
别胡思乱想了
我们需要你，专心辨认
快干活！
干
小美洲狮发了加密的信号
长官，我没法解码
它把我们的位置暴露给伊朗人了
- 狼之歌
- 伊朗人？
- 他们在用主动声呐探测我们
- 副舰长
- 通知一下战斗单位
- 准备战斗
大家动起来！
控制台，你广播一下
进入战斗状态
装备带好！
前部5号发动机，机动
进入完全战斗状态！
重新审查袜子侠，否则不要让他再来
- 那是什么？
- 有直升机！
不要露出皮肤！
这手套，太烂了！
它会从我们上面飞过
直升机不会放过我们的
我们得溜走
潜水员没法进来
有直升机在我做不到
700m后交汇
收到，700m
没希望的，我们走吧
- 潜水员留下的RPG在哪里？
- RPG？
快去找！
主动声纳，方位355
全是声纳，他们要确定我们的位置
多少深度才能躲过声纳？
三次入水声！
深水弹攻击保护！
- 原理屏幕！
- 遮住眼睛！
报告受损情况！
检查所有系统！
声纳不行了
受损情况？推进器还好吗？舵？
舵控制正常
告警系统还好吗？声纳什么时候恢复？
告警系统恢复
一分钟内还会再来
- 准备下潜
- 不，上浮！
- 那样就是自杀
- 上面就是直升机！
长官，RPG来了！
去拿FAMAS自动步枪，快点上浮！
- 我去
- 不，我来！
副舰长，你操纵潜艇！
我们不知道RPG怎么玩
现在副舰长操纵潜艇
前部6号发动机
开动起来
前部6号，开动
气压满！
爬升
还有50米！
40米！
30米！
直升机悬停
在锁定我们的位置
临时命名为旅馆3号
我没法把它解锁
开火！
- 副舰长，潜水员接近了
- 动力降至0
- 朝这开枪！
- 开枪！
不！
... worse hour by hour. ...局势越来越糟糕了
Finland calls for international support against two Russian divisions 昨天早上，芬兰呼吁国际社会
that invaded its southern tip esterday morning. 反对俄罗斯的两个师从南部入侵
Europe's capitals are resigned 而美国对此的态度
to total apathy from America. 显得漠不关心
The president of the Commission announced 欧盟委员会主席宣布
that Russia's aggression should not go "unanswered". 俄罗斯的侵略行为不应得不到解决
So this evening, what does Russia want? 俄罗斯究竟意欲何为
Are we at war? 难道要带来战争吗？
FOUR BLADES 四桨叶
From the whole crew of the Titan. 来自泰坦号全体成员
To France's best CO. 致全法国最好的大副
Thanks. 谢谢
Sorry about that classification. 确认监听的事我很抱歉
I'll find what it was. 我会找出答案的
Put it out of your mind. 别介意
We're small cogs in a big machine. 我们只是机器上的螺丝钉
Rest up now. 现在放松点
I can't even close my eyes. 我甚至睡不着
Without hearing the wolf's call. 即使没有狼嚎
Damn sonar! 该死的声纳
The wolf's call. 狼嚎吗
That'll be my soundtrack when I check out. 就算我上岸了，也会一直跟着我
For the Titan... 为了泰坦号
To the Titan! 泰坦号
Come in. 进来
Morning, captain. 长官，早上好
Captain, I request permission 长官，我请求准许
to continue research ashore 继续上岸研究
and confirm my hypothesis about that transient. 并证实我对那个瞬间的假设
Your hypotheses are done, Chanteraide. 你的假设已经过去了，尚特莱
It's our job to take over analysis. 接管分析是我们的工作
Russian Cougar? Blind alley. 俄罗斯美洲豹？想不通
It's no time to dump on the Russians. 不过没时间去纠结什么俄国人了
It's a powder keg. 那是个火药桶
So what was the transient? 那么那个时候究竟是什么？
Most likely, a drone. 很可能是个无人潜艇
I thought of that too. But I heard an epicycloidal reducer. 我也想到了。但我听到一个外摆线减速器。
Drones don't have reducers. 而无人潜艇没有减速器
And there was life on board. 而且艇上有生命
I heard it. 我听到了
Well, you... 好吧，你...
You hear life. Great. 你听到有生命，不错。
We calculate. Calculations work. 我们计算过了，而计算的结果是
We identified the drone model. 确定是个无人潜艇
The constructor. 不论是构造
The signature. It all checks out. 还是特征，都吻合
I've revoked your database access. 我取消了你的数据库访问权限
I don't understand, sir. I'm just asking to look. 我不明白，长官，我只是请求查看
- I promised captain Grandchamp... - Bullshit promises. -我承诺格兰夏普船长了。 -狗屁承诺
Your flawed classification 你监听的差错
nearly cost us a submarine. 差点害我们损失了一艘潜艇
Here at CIRA, we hang our heads in shame. 我们在CIRA丢尽了脸面
Once and for all, Chanteraide, 一次就够了，尚特莱
this is the military. 这是军队
Not art school. 不是艺术学院
Morning, captain. 早上好，长官
- What does he want? - It's the chopper, I guess. -他想要啥？ -我猜可能是直升机
We're in shit, right? 我们被黑了吧？
Check flies. 检查下校门
All clear. 没问题
You heard the President's speech? 你听了总统的演说了吗？
Morning, admiral. 早上好，上将。
At ease. 稍息
One lemon, two lemons, three lemons. 一个柠檬，两个柠檬，三个柠檬
Jackpot. 撞大运了
First lemon. 柠檬一号
You provoke a crisis in Syria. 你们在叙利亚躲过了一场危机
Based on a flawed classification. 还是基于错误的监听分析
Result... 结果……
A chopper downed in blue water. Our sub barely makes it back. 一架直升机坠毁了，我们让他有来无回
Plus the chief of staff flips his lid. 舰长掀开了潜艇盖子
A biggie. 厉害了
Second lemon. 柠檬二号
The President dispatches ground forces to Finland. 总统正式向芬兰派遣了地面部队
The Russians threaten our ambassador with an atomic warning. 俄国人用原子弹警告了我们的大使
First time ever, all lines of communication down. 有史以来第一次，所有的通信线路都切断了
Third lemon. 柠檬三号
Presidential orders to reinforce our posture. 总统命令捍卫我们的立场
In other words, 换句话说
one nuclear ballistic sub in the water. 一艘核潜艇要出动了
Effective immediately. 立即生效
So three lemons in a row. Jackpot? 三个柠檬说完了，惊喜吗？
Gentlemen, cancel your turkey orders. 先生们，取消你们在土耳其的命令
Fact is, you guys pulled off an act of incredible bravery. 事实上，你们表现得非常勇敢
When I commanded Titan, I'd have done the same. 我指挥泰坦号的时候，也做过同样的事。
So, 所以
Grandchamp... 格兰夏普
you are promoted to a nuclear ballistic missile submarine. 提升你为核潜艇舰长
The Navy's pride and joy is yours. 你是海军的骄傲
The Formidable. 把无畏号交给你了
Make immediate preparations. A 10-week patrol, give or take. 立即准备好，要出海巡航10周，你愿不愿意
Admiral, I promised my wife not to sail again. 上将，我答应我妻子不再出海了。
Grandchamp, 格兰夏普
we're at alert level 6. 我们现在是六级预警
Deterrence for now. No more, no less. 现在的威慑，不多，也不少
But those submarines are my children. 但是这艘潜艇是我的孩子
Only the best will do for them. 我只想要最好的人选
Whatever a president says. 不管总统怎么说
Remember when I recruited you? 还记得我招募你的时候吗？
I said that one day I'd be thanking you. 我说过有一天我会感谢你
At your command, admiral. 听你的，上将
D'Orsi, 多西
you take command of Titan. 你接管泰坦号
You have a problem with that? 有什么问题吗？
- At your command, admiral. - Very good. -听你指挥，上将 -很好
You'll escort Formidable until it goes stealth in blue water. 你负责护送无畏号，直到它消失在深海。
Then await instructions. 随时待命
Conversation ended. 谈话结束了
A 3RD FAILURE WILL RESULT IN ALERT. 三次错误输入将导致警报
At CIRA, we listen, 在CIRA，我们训练听力
we analyse and we interpret. 我们分析并解释我们听到的
We listen, we analyse and we interpret. 我们训练听力，分析，解释
After 60 days at sea? 出海60天以后
Don't you have a wife to walk in the woods? 难道你就没有个老婆陪你在森林漫步？
Top secret. 机密
A wet noise. 潮湿的噪音
A feeling of mass. 一团乱麻一样
May I introduce... 让我介绍一下……
A wet noise. 潮湿的噪音
May I introduce 让我介绍一下
my wife. 我的夫人
- My wife! - Beatrice. -我的夫人！ -碧翠丝
Hello. 你们好
BEATRICE7.
A 3RD FAILURE WILL RESULT IN ALERT. 三次输入错误将导致警报
Change your password 你得改密码了
Or your wife. 或者换个老婆
"Drone F-15. 无人潜艇 F-15
"Analysis by Fourier Transform." “傅里叶变换分析”
"Fourier Transform." “傅里叶变换”
Harmonic Spectra. 谐波谱
- It's a classic. - Never heard of it. -很经典的 -没听说过
Not my field. Ask my colleague who's in tomorrow. 我不负责这块，我同事明天来，可以问问他
It's urgent, actually. 事实上，我很急
- Virginie? Diane's in? - Upstairs. -维吉尼？戴安娜在吗？ -在楼上
- I'll go see. Maybe she'll know. - Thanks. -我去问问，也许她知道。 -谢谢
Was it you, looking for a book? 你在找什么书吗？
Diane, the bookshop owner. 我是戴安娜，书店老板
But I can come back later. 要么我过会儿再来
No... 别……
Sure, sorry, yes. 对了，不好意思，好吧
The Maths book. That's me. 那本数学书，是我要的
- Harmonic Spectra? - Yes. -谐波谱？ -对的
The database says we have it. 数据库显示我们有这本书
But I can't find it right now. 不过我现在找不到
Can you come back tomorrow morning? 你明早再过来可以吗？
At what time tonight? 今晚什么时候？
Say, when is my meeting with that publisher? 说吧，我和那个出版社什么时候会面？
Sorry about the book. In theory, I had it. 关于那本书，对不起，理论上，我有
Turns out, not. 结果呢，又没了
Why a book on spectral harmonies? 怎么会想找一本关于波谱的书？
To analyse a sound. 用来分析声音
You're a musician? 你是音乐家？
- I should've guessed. - No, not a musician, an AWA. -我早该猜到 -不是的，我不是音乐家，我是个AWA
Sorry... 不好意思
Acoustic Warfare Analyst. 就是声学战分析员
No kidding. 不是开玩笑
In real terms, what is acoustic warfare? 实际上，什么是声学战？
Is it dangerous? 有危险吗？
It's identification of acoustic manifestations. 就是听声辩物
Sound signals. 声音信号
Sounds. 还有声音
You have perfect pitch? 你有绝对音感？
Yes, but it's irrelevant. 是的，那不过是小菜一碟
That's something else. 和我说的不是一回事
Alright. 好吧
Sorry. 不好意思
It's intrusive. We don't know each other. 有点唐突了，我们还不算认识
No problem. 没问题
- My actual first name is Prairie. - Sorry? -实际上我的名字叫普莱丽 -啥？
My parents thought it was a typically French name. 我父母觉得这是个典型的法国名字
In fact, it sounds weird. So here I go by Diane. 实际上，它听起来怪怪的，所以我干脆叫戴安娜了
Prairie? 普莱丽？
Alright. 好吧
Sorry, what did... 不好意思，那个……
I can't... 我做不到……
hear a thing. 我听到了什么
The military is redeploying defence forces 军队正在重新部署防御部队
with the mobilisation of three infantry regiments. 动员了三个步兵团
Two squadrons of fighter pilots are on constant alert. 两个战斗飞行中队时刻保持预警
A nuclear ballistic missile submarine ill soon leave port. 一艘核弹道导弹潜艇将很快离开港口
Its departure from Brest is imminent 它即将离开布雷斯特
and its route is top secret. 航线线路属于机密
Michael, can Europe assure its own defence? 迈克尔，欧洲能保证自己的防御吗
That's the big question. 这是个大问题
Many wonder if Finland is worth dying for. 很多人想知道芬兰是否值得为之牺牲
The President has made a decision. 总统已做出决定
"It is not a question of dying for Finland, 这不是为芬兰牺牲的问题了
"but saving the very idea of Europe," 而是拯救欧洲的概念
he declared a few hours ago at the Brussels summit. 他几个小时以前就已经在布鲁塞尔宣布了
So that's acoustic warfare. 这就是声学战
I'm trying to get my head around you living in there. 我想让你知道我住在那里
Stroke of luck, meeting me. 运气好，见到我了
Thank goodness we couldn't find your Maths book. 谢天谢地，我们找不到你的数学书。
Hold on... 等一下
You knew all along you didn't have it? 你本来就知道没那本书？
You planned it. 你故意的
What? 啥？
No. 不是的
It was in my database. 我数据库里有
We never clear the database, that's the problem. 我们从不盘点数据库，这才是问题
You don't believe me? 你不信？
We have a procedure that deletes automatically. 我们会有一个自动删除的进程
A procedure to delete what? 删除什么的进程？
Books? 书吗？
Dismantled submarines. 拆掉的潜艇
They're deleted from the operational database. 会把它们从操作数据库中删除。
But not from the physical archives. 但不包括物理档案
EX-SOVIET BLOC 前苏联集团
That's it. 就是它了
Paired double prop. 双叶双桨
That explains the four blades and the transient. 这就是那个时候四桨叶的解释
Timour III. 帝汶III号
The Soviet terror. 苏联的恐怖
The hell they scrapped it. 他妈的他们把它扔掉了
You're out of your mind. 你疯了吧
Captain... 长官
Look! 你看
Your cellphone. 手机给我
You are under arrest. 你被捕了
Check that file. 看一下这个文件
Captain! 长官
The transient is not a drone. 那个时候的不是无人潜艇
It's a Russian nuclear sub. Timour III. 是俄罗斯核潜艇帝汶III号
Four blades, the same transient. 四桨叶，转瞬即逝
Identical acoustic signatures. 一样的声音信号
Including the asymmetry due to shaft wear. 包括轴磨损引起的不对称。
Decommissioned years ago, in theory. 几年前就退役了，不过是在理论上
In fact stowed away by the Russians. 实际上是俄罗斯人接手了
Until deletion from our database by the procedure. 而程序把它从数据库删掉了
And years later, there it is. 几年后的今天，它又出现了
Untouched. 完好无损
Unclassified, incognito. 无法确认，隐藏起来
Captain! 长官
Shit! 妈的
Your analysis checks out. 你的分析结果出来了
The Brits faced the same rogue situation, same transient. 英国人面临过同样被骗的情况，一样的转瞬即逝
Cross-referencing data leads us to the Timour III. 交互数据将我们引向帝汶III号
Which sheds a different light on your conduct, 也对你之前的行为做出宽恕
even if it remains technically reprehensible. 即使实际上你该受到谴责
After discussions with the Admiral, 经过和上将的讨论
this goes no further. 下不为例
This time. 不过这次
It rankles to tell you, 我很恼火的告诉你
but you may end up on a nuclear ballistic missile sub. 你要到弹道核潜艇上去了
Formidable's captain wants you aboard. 无畏号的舰长要你上船
Formidable's captain wants me? 无畏号舰长要我？
I don't know him. 我不认识他
The new one, you do. 新任舰长，你认识
Grandchamp. 格兰夏普
He threw a hissy fit to get you. 他吵着要你
Don't get over-excited. There's a test first. 别兴奋过头了，你得先通过测试
The Admiral has the last word. 上将最后说了
Get into uniform. Training starts today. 穿上制服，今天就开始训练
Yes, sir. 是，长官
Russian sonar, low frequency. Type Shark. 俄罗斯声纳，低频，代码鲨鱼
Vessel? 是船吗？
K-138.
New generation. 最新一代
Plus five dolphins, two babies. 另外有五只海豚，两个孩子
Something there. 有东西
Submarine. 潜艇
Nuclear propulsion. 核动力
Attack submarine. 攻击型潜艇
Not American. 不是美国的
Not British. 也不是英国的
It could be the Kiev. 可能是基辅级
No, there's an egg-whisk tone. 不对，有打蛋器的声音
Nuclear ballistic missile submarine. 核弹道潜艇
SSBN.
Before going stealth. 还没开始秘密行动
If it had gone stealth, you wouldn't hear it, Socks. 如果它开始行动了，你是听不到的，小鬼
Even the machine wouldn't detect it. 甚至连仪器都探测不到
Anyway... 这么说吧
FYI, it's... 如果确认的话，他是……
Formidable. 无畏号
Really? 确定吗？
Not Invincible? 不是无敌号吗？
They're identical, constructed together. 他们是同型号的，一起建造的
Check spectral analysis. Formidable first. 比对频谱的话，优先判断是无畏号
Then the other. 那么其他的呢？
You see any difference? 你发现了什么不同？
Was Formidable's turbine remachined due to damage? 无畏号的涡轮是不是损坏了重新加工过？
The dream team. 梦之队
- Ok, Socks? - D'Orsi. -好了吗？小鬼？ -多西
Sorry, admiral, didn't see you. 对不起，上将，没看到你在
Well... 好吧……
Chanteraide, confirmed. Boarding tomorrow, 4 am. 尚特莱，确认，明早四点登艇
Well played, son. 干得漂亮，孩子
- You did your medical? - All good. -你体检过了吗？ -没问题
Not on antidepressants? 没吃什么抗抑郁药吗？
Shows up in your urine. 有尿检呢
The SSBN 弹道导弹核潜艇
isn't the Love Boat. 不是有爱的潜艇
The mission is, ready to fire in under an hour on presidential orders. 其任务就是等待总统的指令，随时准备开火
You're the country's life insurance. 你们是国家的安全保障
Copy that. 明白
3,000 years of civilisation did not bring peace. 3000年的文明没有带来和平
Only deterrence... 只有威慑……
Effective deterrence depends on 有效的威慑取决于
sailors keeping quiet. 水手们保持安静
"Diwel didrouz maro pa denn." 迪威尔·迪德罗兹·马罗·帕丹。
What's that? 啥意思
The SSBN motto. SSBN的座右铭
Your new home. 你的新去处会告诉你
"Invisible and silent, I bring death." 隐形消声，我是死神
Good luck, son. 祝你好运，小鬼
Keep on the PIM. 保持联络
Captain. 长官
Titan, red company. 泰坦号，红队
Attention! 注意
Eyes front. 向前看
Company mustered and correct. At your command, sir. 所有成员到齐，等待命令，长官
Welcome aboard. 欢迎上船
Formidable blue company, attention! 无畏号，蓝队，注意
XO, 传令官
take over. 接管
XO, take over. 传令官，接管
At ease. 稍息
Attention! 注意
Roll call. Respond present and board. 点名，报到后上船
- Abbad! - Present. -阿巴德 -到
- Aboulker! - Present. -阿博尔科 -到
The doc found cannabis in your urine sample. 医生在你的尿样中发现大麻
He declared you unfit to serve. 他觉得你不适合随舰
I will not challenge it. 我不打算反驳
I must be able to rely on each man operating at 100%. 我必须100%信赖每个人
Captain Grandchamp aboard! 格兰夏普船长登艇
Stop! Gates closing. 停下，关门了
Fortress procedure! 进入要塞
Loc, give me a hand! 洛克，帮我一把
Move! 行动
Coming through. 快来
- What's going on? - Nuke R-30. Fired from Bering Sea. -怎么回事？ -核弹R-30，从白令海发射了
The Russians are moving! 俄国人行动了
Keep the info coming. 保持信息跟进
Faster! 快！
President's office. 总统办公室
The President is at Jupiter Command. 总统在木星指挥部
Upgrade to alert level 10. 警报提升至10级
Tell Grandchamp to go stealth immediately. 让格兰夏普立刻开始潜航
Keep the info coming! 继续跟进信息
25 minutes left. 只有25分钟了
FORTRESS PROCEDURE ACTIVATED 要塞程序启动
Formidable at 6,000 m, opening. 无畏号，距离6000米，打开。
Copy. 收到
Very good. 很好
What's that trace, north? 那是什么痕迹，北面？
Nothing. The 15. 没什么，15号
Identify contact 11. 确认连接11号
We have 11, bearing 2-3-9. 11号在线，位置2-3-9
Echo, Foxtrot. E，F
Echo, X-ray. E，X
Formidable assuming stealth mode, 无畏号进入潜航模式了
thanks us for our company and wishes us the best. 感谢我们的陪伴，并祝我们一切顺利
Salute Formidable's formidability and wish her well. 敬礼，也祝无畏号一切顺利
Copy, captain. 收到，长官
Plotting priority on 12. 优先标绘12号
Mission accomplished.No further instructions. 任务完成，没有进一步指示
If not on watch, stand down. 如果不在值班的，就下来吧
Guys... 伙计们……
Now or never for a workout or shower. 做做锻炼或者洗个澡
Or even both. 也可以两样一起
In the right order. 不过别弄错顺序
Formidable, bearing 0-2-3. Losing her. 无畏号，位置0-2-3，消失了
NATO satellites confirm impact on French territory. 北约卫星确认目标法国本土
- Paris spoke to the US? - They say it's 100% Russian. -巴黎通知美国了吗？ -他们说肯定是俄罗斯
Coming from Russian waters doesn't make it Russian. 从俄罗斯水域发射也不能证明就是俄国人的吧
Russia signals it's not them. 俄国人否认是他们发射的
It's not like they'd admit it. 他们当然不会承认
Paris orders not to raise the alarm, while impact can be avoided. 巴黎命令不要升级警报，直接用弹道导弹拦截
By interception with a ballistic missile. 以避免打击
They've tested that system? 他们测试过那套系统了？
- No. - Clay-pigeon shooting. -没 -那打个屁
I hate clay-pigeon shooting.
Sir, our sub in the Bering Sea says it recorded missile launch. 长官，我们白令海的潜艇记录下了导弹发射
- Launch vessel had a four-blade prop. - Four blades? -发射的是一艘四桨叶潜艇 四桨叶？-
Timour III. Put it on that machine. 帝汶III号，把它放到仪器上
I want its signature.Where's CIRA and his ears? 给我那个信号，CIRA的金耳朵在哪？
Not inside here. 不在这里
Fuck, we need him now! 擦，我现在就要人
We have no one to listen? 没人能听辨了吗？
Admiral... 上将……
Socks, what the hell? 小鬼，还站着干嘛？
Isn't it spliff time? 浪费时间吗？
Grab a seat and listen in. 找个位置开始听吧
Better and better. 再好不过了
I'm sending sub and launch audio. 我把潜艇和发射的音频发过来
Well? 好了吗？
I have audio. 音频收到
Yes, that's Timour III. 没错，是帝汶III号
You're sure? 你确定？
- Grandchamp's in stealth mode? - Affirmative. -格兰夏普进入潜航了吗？ -是的
Transmit info to the Chief of Staff.Russian launch confirmed. 告诉舰长，俄罗斯的发射已经确认
Here we go. 来吧
Buckle up. 系好安全带
Depth 500 m. 深度500米
Captain, clear ahead, bearing 1-5-3. 舰长，前方畅通，方位1-5-3
Anti-tracking manoeuvres complete.We're undetectable. 反跟踪操作完成，我舰无法被探测
Very good. 很好
Engine ahead 2. 前进2
- Assume Patrol Quiet State. - Ahead 2. -进入静态巡航 -前进2
All compartments, assume Patrol Quiet State. 所有舱室，进入静态巡航
Report to Control. 报告控制室
- Machine room, copy - Torpedo section, copy. -机舱，收到 -鱼雷舱，收到
Two incoming messages for CO and XO. 有两条给大副和传令官的讯息
Superencrypted messages. 超加密邮件
On my way for decryption. 我负责解码
XO. 传令官
Captain. 舰长
IMMEDIATE LAUNCH ORDER 紧急发射指令
J19.
6ZFU.
Authenticated. 已验证
K08.
AVY0.
Authenticated. 已验证
Initiating ballistic missile interception. 启动弹道导弹拦截
Arming launch pad. 启动发射台
Adjusting launch azimuth. 修正发射方位
I have the R-30 recording. 记录到R-30
Interceptor ready for launch. 拦截器准备发射
Ten... 10
Nine... 9
Eight... 8
Seven... 7
Six... 6
Five... 5
- Four... - Something's off with the R-30 launch. -4 -有东西从R-30分离了
One... 1
Interceptor launched. 拦截发射
Target at 150 km. 目标150KM
100 km. 100KM
50 km. 50KM
20 km.
Interceptor and missile intersect in... 拦截导弹交汇中……
Ten... Nine... 10……9……
Eight... 8……
Seven... Six... 7……6……
Five... Four... 5……4……
Three... Two... 3……2……
One... 1……
R-30 missile destruction failed. R-30拦截失败
Mission failed. 任务失败
Estimated impact zone? 预计打击区域
Update the scenario. Let's go! 更新方案，行动
- Admiral, an anomaly. - What? -上将，异常情况 -什么？
- There's a... - Spit it out! -有一个…… -快说
Missile first-stage separation is off. 导弹的第一级已经分离了
- The booster should... - Chanteraide! -助推器应该…… -尚特莱
Too late. 太晚了
Admiral, I... 上将，我……
I've heard R-30 launches. This is not one. 我听过R-30发射，这个不是
Not with a payload, at least. 至少没有有效载荷
Who let him in? 谁让他进来的
Check the spectral. 查一下频谱
Is he high? 是高音吗
Please, just take a look. 求求你，就看一眼
Cut the crap here! 别胡扯了
Go and listen! 那你去听
Well? 对吗？
He's right. 他是对的
Weight-resistance ratio is off. 重量阻力比不对
- The issue's the weight. - Too heavy or light? -问题在于重量 -重还是轻？
Too light. 20%. 轻了20%
No nuclear warhead? 没有核弹头
Yes. That explains the ratio. 是的，频率可以解释
Come on. You too, Socks. 来吧，还有你，小鬼
Get me the Chief of Staff at Jupiter Command. 给我连接木星指挥部最高长官
Admiral, can you hold? 上将，你能等等吗？
No, get a message to him. It's urgent! 不行，告诉他，我这边很紧急
Suspend communications. Incoming and outgoing. 暂停通讯，输入以及输出
Yes, sir. 是，长官
Control to Radio, comms suspended. 控制室呼叫通信室，暂停通讯
Do not copy. 不用回答
This is the captain. 我是舰长
A major attack is ongoing on French territory. 法国领土正在遭受打击
Our orders have changed. 我们的指令变了
The President has ordered me to effect a counterstrike. 总统命令我们实施反击
I authenticated the order with the executive officer. 我和传令官对命令进行了互证
XO, here. 传令官，过来
I confirm authentication of the President's orders. 我确认接到了总统的命令
Admiral? 上将？
General, a submarine heard the R-30 launch in the Bering.将军，一艘潜艇在白令监听到了R-30发射
My analysts assert nuclear payload is absent. 我的分析员判断没有核弹头载荷
I repeat. The missile is empty. 重复一遍，导弹是空的
You vouch for your analysts? 你为你的分析师担保？
Yes. 是的
Three hypotheses... 三个假设……
- General, Washington calling! - I'll take it. -将军，华盛顿来电！ -接进来
- General! - Sorry, admiral, the Secretary of State. -将军 -等一下，上将，国家机密
Shit! 妈的
Why would the Russians fire an empty missile? 俄国人干嘛要发射空弹头？
A counterstrike is inevitable. It's absurd! 引人反击吗？太荒谬了
- General? - Equation's changed. -将军？ -平衡被打破了
According to the Americans, 根据美国人的说法
Two years ago, funds were wired to an ex-Russian admiral, 两年前，有基金被电汇给了一个前俄罗斯上将
formerly in command of the Pacific fleet. 120 million euros. 1.2亿欧元，他还指挥过太平洋舰队。
The going rate for a submarine? 钱是用来买潜艇？
For a scrapped Timour III, sure. 对的，买报废的帝汶III号
Via various offshore accounts, the money came from Al-Jadida. 通过各种离岸账户，钱来自于加迪达。
The US forgot to mention it. 美国人忘了提这茬
- The Timour III is in jihadist hands? - Looks that way. -那么帝汶III是在圣战者手里了？ -看那边
That's why there's no nuclear payload. 所以没有核弹头
And we have riposted. 而我们还击了
They're triggering nuclear war. 他们想触发核战
Very smart. 真狡猾
I'll get back to you. 等下再找你
The perfect trap. 完美的圈套
Down to the Timour III buzzing you in Syria. 要不是你再叙利亚听到过帝汶III号
To be sure we'd peg the launch on the Russians. 我们肯定要确信是俄国人了
It was all so we'd reclassify it? 我们到此为止了吗？
General? 将军？
I'm with the President. Cancel the strike. 我在总统旁边，停止核打击
The Navy has procedures that we respect unfortunately. 不幸的是，海军已经开始行动了
But there is no procedure for recalling an SSBN strike. 而我们没法叫停已经开始的核潜艇打击
It's the principle of deterrence. 这是威慑的规则
I know that. Try to contact the submarine captain. 我知道，尝试联系潜艇舰长
From reception of the strike order, 接到打击的命令以后
the sub's captain must consider anyone who intervenes 潜艇舰长会把每个介入者
as potentially working for the enemy. 都看作是敌人指使的
Nobody can prevent Grandchamp from launching that missile. 没人能阻止格兰夏普发射导弹
Not me, not you. 我不行，你也不行
Not even the President. 就连总统也不行
Our only option is to neutralise the captain. 那么阻止舰长是我们唯一的选择
General, I am under your command 将军，你可以下命令
but I cannot do what I cannot do. 可我做不到还是做不到
How long before Grandchamp launches? 格兰夏普出发多久了
Less than one hour. 不到一小时
It's that or apocalypse. 要么阻截他，要么毁灭世界
From now on, our sole priority is this strategic strike. 从现在起，我们的首要任务就是这次战略打击
It's a turning-point in history. We have all trained 这是历史的转折点，我们都是受过训练的。
for this situation. 训练就是为了眼下这种情况
The time has come 该来的还是来了
to do our duty. Your duty. 各尽其责，坚守岗位
Formidable, blue company, 无畏号，蓝队
I'm relying on you. Over and out. 拜托各位了，再一次
I spent my life teaching kids to respect the procedure. 我用一辈子教会孩子们遵守程序规定
To keep the country safe, trust the system. 捍卫国家安全，相信整个系统
Now I neutralise those kids? 现在你让我阻止他们
Action stations! 行动状态
You're head of our nuclear force. 你是核部队的头儿
Grandchamp will listen. 格兰夏普会听你的
If we abandon procedure, our deterrence will be discredited. 如果我们中止进程，我们的核威慑将不复存在
Grandchamp cannot obey me. 格兰夏普不会听我的
I could be manipulated. 我也可能是被人操纵的
It's why there's the procedure. 这就是程序规则
Admiral, you say it year after year. 上将，你年复一年的说
It's drilled into us. 耳朵都听起茧了
"If it happens, there'll be doubts and decoys. “如果发生了，就会有怀疑和欺骗
"And men demanding we recall..." 有人会要去我们召回
Hundreds of millions of lives are at risk! 那么上亿人就危在旦夕
- Don't crack! - Cut it out! -别开玩笑！ -别说了！
You think I don't know? 你以为我不知道？
Formidable's gone stealth. We've no idea where. 无畏号在潜航，而我们束手无策
It just went stealth. It can't be far from Titan. 它刚开始潜航，距离泰号坦应该不远
No sonar can detect it. 声纳探测不到它
What do you suggest? 你有什么建议
It's now, admiral. 上将，就是现在了
No, admiral. 不，上将
Couldn't you wear normal shoes on a day like this? 像今天这样的日子你就不能穿一双普通的鞋？
Base was out of them? 哪怕是基地在外面？
Going to the dogs. 还真是形影不离
Not surprising coming from you. 你一点也不惊讶
Didn't you spend three months in a sub in your socks? 你在那艘潜艇里当了三个月的小鬼？
You certainly earned your nickname. 看来你的绰号改不了了
Nice. What goes around comes around. 很好，什么事都会发生
Admiral, this is CIRA. 上将，这里是CIRA
R-30 impact in the Compigne forest. R-30落在了森林里
No damage reported. 没有造成打击损失
No nuclear warhead. 也没有核弹头
Admiral, to what do I owe the honour? 上将，什么风把你吹来了
To all hands, this is Alfost! 所有人注意，我是阿尔弗斯特
We fell into a trap. 我们中了圈套
Formidable was ordered to fire a nuclear missile at Russia. 无畏号被派往俄罗斯发射核弹
If the missile is launched, the Russians counter. 如果导弹发射，俄国人还击
I'll let you join the dots. 那么一切都晚了
What I'm about to say is hard to take in, and harder to say. 我要说的难以做到，更难以置信
Our priority is to stop Grandchamp launching. 我们的首要任务是阻止格兰夏普的发射
By all means necessary. 以所有的可能
This defies procedure, why trust you? 这不符合程序，为什么相信你
Your Captain speaking. 我是船长
Action stations! 开始行动
In position. 各就各位
Formidable's last known position? 无畏号最后已知的位置在哪？
They went stealth in sector 7. 他们在7区开始潜航了
Sector 7? 7区？
In his shoes, where'd you go? 他走了，你们准备去哪？
Grandchamp is pure reason. 格兰夏普的理由很简单
He calculates for optimal outcomes. 他计算出最佳结果
Optimal in this case? 当前情况下最佳的？
First up, whatever saves lives. 无论如何，救人第一
Saves lives? Meaning? 救人？什么意思？
With nuclear missiles, 用核弹头
to avoid collateral damage you reset position at launch? 为了避免附带的损害，你在发射时重置了位置？
It's not protocol but... 这个没有规定，不过……
To keep the hit clean, it's best to fix position before launch. 为了保持命中率，最好在发射前确定位置
He'll do that. 他会这么做的
For sure. 可以肯定
But he can't surface. 但是他不能浮出水面
He needs a magic point. 他需要一个悬浮点
Bring up nearby magic points. 最近的悬浮点在哪？
- Magic points? - True, we don't have them. -悬浮点？ -实际上，这条船上没有相关资料
Only SSNBs do. 只有弹道核潜艇上才能找到
I commanded an SSNB. I need to remember. 我指挥过核潜艇，我得回忆一下
Sector 7. 7区
Sector 8, two of them. 8区，有两个
Mapped peaks. 绘制峰值
Calypso here and Circe here. 卡莉普索在这里，瑟曦在这里
ETA? 预计到达时间？
Calypso, for him, ten minutes. 卡莉普索，对他来说，需要十分钟
For us, 13. 而我们需要13分钟
- Too late. - Circe... -太晚了 -瑟曦……
We arrive pretty much simultaneously. 我们几乎同时到达
We need him to go for Circe. 我们得让他们去瑟曦
Circe. 瑟曦
- Chops... - Admiral? -通讯员 -在，上将
Transmit to base to send two aircraft over Calypso. 联系基地派两架飞机去卡莉普索
They cover the sea with sonobuoys and crank it up. 让他们用声纳覆盖海面，调高音量
See if the octopuses like AC/DC. 看看章鱼是不是像AC/DC
Yes, sir. 是，长官
Transmitting code 5, confirmed Alfost. 联络代码5，确认阿尔弗斯特
Grandchamp winds up in a moshpit 格兰夏普进了一个舞池
and has to swing over to Circe. 就不得不往瑟曦去
XO, take us to Circe. 传令官，去瑟曦
Romeo. 罗密欧
Plotter, bearing to Circe? 绘图员，给我瑟曦的位置
Alpha.
2-3-2.
CALYPSO MAGIC POINT 47N 8W 卡莉普索悬浮点 47N 8W
Analysis? 分析结果如何？
Sonobuoys. Type Dicasse. 声纳浮标，迪卡西型的
Lots of them. 有很多
Dicasse, that's our Navy. What the hell! 迪卡西，是我们的海军，搞什么？
It's weird. 真奇怪？
It's gotta be Alfost. 可能是阿尔弗斯特
Captain? 舰长？
Distance from Magic Point 2? 距离2号悬浮点多远？
Circe, 6,000 m at 2-8-4. 瑟曦，6000米，方位2-8-4
Captain takes the boat. 现在船长接管
Set course 2-8-4. Ahead 5. 坐标2-8-4，前进5
Captain, someone's messing with us. 船长，有人在和我们捣乱
Maybe we should fire with less precision. Time's short. 也许我们应该降低射击精度，时间不多了
No, we continue the sequence. 不，我们按程序来
- I'll be in position. - Very good. -那我待命 -很好
Missile room. Running checks. 导弹舱，发射检查
Magic point 2,500 m. 悬浮点2500米
Why no insignia? 为什么不戴上徽章？
Don't you want to die looking good? 你们不想死得漂亮点？
What's this eyesore? You need comfort? 在这碍什么眼，你想要多舒服？
You're ballet dancers? 你是跳芭蕾的吗？
If the computer's bust, why isn't it replaced? 如果电脑不好使，干嘛不换一台？
Because this is France. 法国国情
Only one works. 就一个人干活
Arriving at Circe. Let's reset now. 到达瑟曦，现在复位
- Chops, take over. - Yes, sir. -通讯员，你接管。 -遵命
Stand by to reset. 准备复位
Ready. 就绪
Reset. 复位
Reset complete. 重置完成
Position margin of error, 100 m. 位置误差范围，100米
Optimal margin reached. 已到达最佳发射位置
Attain launch depth. When we're there, we fire the missile. 调整发射深度，到位后发射导弹
Waking missile. 导弹启动
Magic point 1,000 m. Entering reset zone. 悬浮点1000米，正在通过复位区域
At this distance, try the underwater phone. 保持这个距离，试试用水下电话
Wait! 等一下
Do that and it's simple. They'll hear and locate us. 那样做很简单，他们会听到并找到我们
Either they answer or they apply protocol 然后要么回答，要么按照规定程序
and torpedo us. 向我们发射鱼雷
Stand by to engage. 准备接触
Heuristic, as methods go. 没有别的办法了？
Quit the philosophy. 要么别干了
Yes, sir. 遵命，长官
But it's Grandchamp. 可那是格兰夏普
- Torpedo, prepare to fire. - Copy. -鱼雷准备发射 -收到
Tubes one to four ready. 1-4号鱼雷准备就绪
Transmitting by TUUM. 通过TUUM频段传输
Copy that. TUUM. 收到，TUUM
As soon as you hear a sound, give the alert. 一听到声音，就给出警告
Copy. 收到
I have three frequencies, no bearing. 我有三个频率，没有方位
- Check the lawn. - Marked frequencies? -检查一下海底 -标记频率
Yes. Possible submarine. 是，可能是潜艇
Watch out, poss-sub! 注意，疑似潜艇
Control, get me the XO. 给我接传令官
XO, get back here to Control. Poss-sub contact. 传令官，回控制室来，发现疑似潜艇
Copy that. 收到
Examine each trace. 诊断所有频段
TUUM!
The poss-sub. Plot it. 疑似潜艇，标记它
Bearing on TUUM? Cross-check. 确定TUUM位置，用交叉法核查
- 0-2-8. - Bearing 0-2-8! -0-2-8 -方位0-2-8
- 1,000 m. - Torpedo standing by. -1000米 -鱼雷准备
Bravo Charlie 3. 布拉沃查理3
This is Zulu Delta 4. 我是祖鲁德塔4
Do you copy? 听到吗？
Zulu Delta 4, that's Titan. We take it. 祖鲁德塔4，是泰坦号，接进来
Captain, we have orders to launch. There are rules. 船长，我们接到了发射的命令，有规定的。
- No TUUM. - It's D'Orsi. My men! -不，TUUM -是多西，我的人
Why's he want us to transmit? 他为什么要现在联络？
- To detect us. - D'Orsi wouldn't do that. -来探测我们 -多西不会这么做
Why did they surface earlier? 他们为什么这么早暴露？
Someone boarded. Who? 有人上船了，谁？
This is Zulu Delta 4. 我是祖鲁德塔4
Do you copy? 听到吗？
The President's order is irrevocable. 总统的命令是不可撤销的。
This is Zulu Delta 4. 我是祖鲁德塔4
Deactivate TUUM. 停用TUUM
Captain to crew! 船长现在命令
We continue launch procedure. 我们继续发射
200 m from launch depth. 距离发射深度200米
In any case, it's impossible. 无论如何，这不可能
Formidable, stealth, Grandchamp. 无畏号，潜航，格兰夏普
Three lemons. 三个柠檬
Slightly stronger background noise. 略强的背景噪音
No engine information. 没有引擎的声音
No information is information. 没有声音就意味着……
It's him. 是他了
Bearing 2-3-9. 方位2-3-9
- Formidable at 2-3-9. - Maximum distance 1,200 m. -无畏号方位2-3-9 -最大距离1200米
At that distance, he heard our call. 这个距离上，他听到我们的呼叫了
He's ready to launch. 他在准备发射
We have no choice but to engage first. 看来没选择了，只能先发制人了
Hold on, I... 等一下，我……
I've lost him. 声音消失了
Shit! 妈的
Find him, Chanteraide. 找到它，尚特莱
Time's burning up. Let's go! 火烧眉毛了，快啊
Come on, Chanteraide. 来吧，尚特莱
Death's only beauty is victory. 唯一死的漂亮的方法就是胜利
We must engage. 我们必须先发制人
We must engage! 我们必须先发制人
I'm trying. 我在努力
We must engage. 我们必须先发制人
I can't do it. 我做不到
Son, come back here. 孩子，回来
Get the other AWA. Stay focused. 另找个监听的，集中注意力
- They're our brothers. - No! -他们是我们自己人 -不！
They're sailors with orders to launch. 他们是接到了发射指令的水手
Come on, we have them. They're right there. 来吧，我们找到他们了，就在那里
Come on. 来啊
Control, 控制室
prep torpedo tube for underwater vehicle. 为水下航行器准备鱼雷管
- What for? - To talk to Grandchamp. -干啥？ -去和格兰夏普谈谈
You knock in Morse, he lets you in? 你敲个莫尔斯码他就会让你进去？
Your options, besides firing? 你有别的选择吗？除了开火
The pressure's too extreme. 压力太大了
Titan submariners love pressure. 泰坦号的船员就喜欢压力
Bullshit! This is real life! 扯淡，现实一点
With that logic in Syria, we'd be dead. 都那么想的话，我们在叙利亚就已经死了
I know what I'm doing. 我知道我在干嘛
Take care of Titan. 照看好泰坦号
They're my children, too. 他们也是我的孩子
D'Orsi. 多西
Good luck. 祝你好运
Track him. 跟着他
Stay focused. Come on! 给我全神贯注
Delta section, prep vehicle. No questions asked. 三角区，准备潜水器，别多问
Last chance. 最后的机会
Very strange noise, bearing 0-1-5. 很奇怪的噪音，方位0-1-5
Like a propeller with flippers. 像一个带鳍的螺旋桨
A combat swimmer. 战斗蛙人
Clearly, Titan is hostile and its manoeuvres are offensive. 很明朗了，泰坦号是敌人，它采取的是攻击行动
We must engage. 我们得还击
Captain? 船长？
Torpedoes ready. 鱼雷准备
Standing by to engage, captain. 准备开火，船长
Engage Titan! 向泰坦号发射
Fire! 着火了
Delta section! 三角区
Fire in Delta section! 三角区着火了
Masks on! 戴面具
Admiral, hull's intact. 上将，船体没受损
We're watertight but fire in Delta section. 水密没问题，不过三角区着火了
Send more men to Delta. 多派些人去三角区
- We've lost Formidable. - White noise. -无畏号跟丢了 -白噪音
Need a fixed position! 需要修正位置
Where's D'Orsi? 多西哪儿去了？
Only your ears can save us. 只有你的耳朵能救我们了
I trust you. 我相信你
Chanteraide! Breathe! 尚特莱，深呼吸
Inserting splice. 插入接头
All clear? 都准备好了？
Standing by. 待命
Very good. 很好
Weapons officer? 武器员？
When you're ready, sir. 就等你了，长官
Control, this is XO. 控制室，我是传令官
Ready to enter President's code. 准备输入总统代码
Copy that. 收到
Captain, 船长
when you're ready. 等你下令
Countdown to enter President's code. 输入总统代码倒计时
Ten... Nine... 10……9……
Enter President's code. 输入总统代码
Code confirmed. 代码确认
Three minutes! 三分钟
Let's go. 来吧
Silence! 安静
Missile alignment underway. Maintain course. 导弹对准进行中，保持航向。
- I repeat, maintain course. - Copy. -重复，保持航向 -收到
Helm is at 2-7-0. 航向保持2-7-0
Open missile door! 打开导弹舱
Copy. 收到
Torpedo. 鱼雷
Torpedo alert! 鱼雷警报
Fired by Titan. Captain, break away. 是泰坦号发射的，船长，得撤了
Negative. Alignment underway. 不行，正在进行校准
- How long to launch? - 160 secs! -还有多久发射 -160 秒
- How long to torpedo impact? - 120 secs. -鱼雷要多久 -120秒
- Torpedo is wire-guided. - We must break away. -鱼雷有引导线 -我们必须得撤了
Let's make that wire snap. Torpedo! 把线打断，发射鱼雷
Engage Titan! 射击，泰坦
Urgent launch, tube 2! 紧急启动，2号鱼雷管
Bearing 0-5-9! 位置0-5-9
TORPEDO FIRED 鱼雷发射
Torpedo alert! Headed straight for us, 900 m! 鱼雷警报，冲我们来了，900米
Quiet. 安静
Quiet! 安静
We expected it. 早料到了
- We must break away. - It's what he wants. -我们得撤了 -他就想要我们……
To snap the wire. I stay put. 别切断引导线，我们待在原地
Maintain course. 保持航向
Go on, back off! 快撤吧
Snap your fucking wire! 切断你那该死的引导线
Captain, Titan is not breaking away. 船长，泰坦号不肯撤离
Torpedo, 700 m. 鱼雷，700米
- 700 m! - Accelerating on audio. -700米！ -音频加速了
Veer right. Dive! 右转，下潜
Chops! 通讯员
Veer right! Dive! 右转下潜！
Chops, what the hell! 通讯员，你干啥！
Break away. We're gonna die! 快撤，要死了
Don't let me down. 别搞砸了
Cut it out! 快切断它
We gotta break away! 我们得撤了
- We're gonna die! - Stay focused. -要死了！ -集中注意力
Focus on your screens! 盯着你们的屏幕
Captain, we're gonna catch it. 船长，就快击中我们了
Masks on! 带上面罩
Hallowed be thy name 上帝保佑
Masks on! 戴上面罩
Your will be done on Earth as it is in Heaven 死在地球宛若天堂
Men! 伙计们
It was an honour to sail with you. 和你们在一起我感到荣耀
We'll see this through! 自始至终
I'll take guidance on manual. 接下来由我人工引导
Bring up torpedo telemetry. 启动鱼雷遥测
Torpedo headed straight for target. 鱼雷直奔目标
Time to missile launch? 还有多久发射
40 seconds. 40秒
Buy ten more. 再争取10秒
Deploy decoy! 部署诱饵
FORMIDABLE 无畏号
Solution uncertain. Target moving. 轨迹改变，目标移动了
- No, that's a decoy. - Sure, sir? -不，那是诱饵 -确定吗，长官？
- Machine says no decoy. - Come left. -仪器没有现实诱饵 -向左
- I know. Formidable's my baby. - Coming left. -我了解无畏号，就像我的孩子一样 -向左
Captain, torpedo headed straight for us. 船长，鱼雷直冲我们来了
Cut engines and sonar. We play dead. 切断发动机和声纳，我们装死
- It's gone! - Watch. It'll reappear there. -它不见了 -看好，它会重新出现在那里
Hold on. 等一下
Missile! 导弹！
Launch authorised in 20 secs! 授权发射还有20秒
Torpedo impact, 15 secs. 鱼雷还有15秒
It's over, sir. 完蛋了，长官
FORMIDABLE 无畏号
- Adopted! - On target, solution positive. -就这样 -看见目标了，方向正确
Target reached, 10 secs! 10秒命中目标
Blow air tanks. Create double target! 气舱排气，双重目标
Captain, launch authorised! 船长，可以发射了
Survivors? 有活的吗
Anyone? 有人吗？
Anyone answer me? 回答啊
Socks! 小鬼
C'mon, Socks! 来，小鬼
LAUNCH AUTHORISED 准备发射
Control room, XO here. Do you copy? 控制室，我是传令官，收到吗？
Captain, do you copy? 船长，听得到吗？
Control, do you copy? 控制室，收到吗
Control, answer me! 控制室，请回答
TUUM active. Sending distress message! TUUM激活，发送遇险信息
Negative, Chops. 不可以，通讯员
First, we launch the missile. 我们得先发射导弹
No air in circuit! 没有空气回路了
Masks off! 脱掉面罩
Monoxide. 一氧化碳
Air's contaminated, sir! 空气被污染了，长官
Evacuate control room. 疏散控制室
Evacuate! 疏散
Come on, captain. 快来，船长
Stay with me. We're going up. 跟着我，我们上去
Captain... 船长
Captain, Chanteraide here. 船长，我是尚特莱
If you hear me... 如果你能听到
You always trusted me. 你一直都相信我
Trust me one last time. 那么最后信我一次
I beg you, do not launch a missile. 我求你，别发射导弹
It would be a grievous error. 这是个严重的错误
Most likely, these are my last words. 也许，这是我最后的遗言
I hear the wolf's call. 我听见了狼嚎
Farewell, captain. 船长，永别了
Take it. 拿着
- You, admiral. - No, we'll get you out of here. -上将 -不，我们得把你弄出去
Socks, put it on. Now! 小鬼，穿上
Your ears will blow. Say goodbye to your eardrums. 你的耳朵会受压，和你的鼓膜说再见吧。
In there! 去那儿
Let's go! 走吧
THE WOLF'S CALL
Subtitles: Simon John