1873 in the Drôme
Here, Joseph.
For your collection.
You can keep it.
The name is illegible.
Joseph, I know that
the world of people scares you.
But you must come.
Come on now.
For Rosalie. For your son.
We are gathered here, this afternoon,
to bid farewell to Rosalie Cheval,
née Rosalie Revol,
wife of Joseph Ferdinand Cheval,
postal employee,
and mother of Cyrille Cheval.
Victoire and I are too old
to look after our grandson.
He will go to Lyon,
to live with his aunt and uncle.
How will you do your rounds?
What will you do with the lad?
End of story.
Cyrille, go say goodbye
to your father.
Hurry up.
Say goodbye.
Goodbye, Dad.
- Auguste.
- Yes?
Can you take it for me?
Of course. But why do you
always bring me your post?
Cheval passes your house every day.
You saw it yourself.
He didn't even shed a tear for Rosalie.
- He's an animal.
- He just doesn't have any tears left.
Well, he scares me.
Listen, Félicienne,
that's just the way he is...
withdrawn.
Extraordinary discovery
in the Cambodian jungle:
the temples
of Angkor.
Angkor.
Angkor...
Hello.
Which way to Rufus Comblet's house?
Behind the house, follow the path,
turn right at the crossing.
Are you new?
I've never seen you before.
Philomène Richaud.
Postman Cheval.
They've extended my rounds.
Wait.
It's a steep path to the Comblet's.
More?
What do you think about as you walk?
It must take a long time.
Well, thank you.
I'll be off.
See you tomorrow,
Postman Cheval.
Right at the crossing!
Did you see widow Richaud?
- Yes.
- How is she doing up there?
I don't know.
She's alone.
I dream.
Pardon?
The other day, you asked me
what I do when I walk.
Well, I dream.
- And you don't get bored?
- No.
I'm happy when I walk.
Earlier, I was imagining
building a house in the forest,
with branches,
leaves and flowers.
It must be a pretty house.
Have you heard
of the Mayan temples?
No.
There are some
in Picturesque magazine.
Are you hurt?
- No, it's nothing.
- No, it's not nothing, it's...
It's infected.
It's... empty.
What more does it need?
A little sweep, perhaps.
The bed by the window...
I like it.
I have some pale red fabric left.
It will look nice here.
It's so beautiful.
Where did you learn to do that?
I was an apprentice baker
in Romans, in Valence.
The important thing is your palm.
You must forget your fingers.
- Can I taste it?
- No, that's not allowed.
It's better like that.
Taste it.
Go on, taste it.
I have some handsome eggplants.
And some zucchini over there.
- I even have some sage.
- How lucky!
You'll have food this winter.
- They say it'll be harsh.
- I heard.
Thank you.
- What does your Joseph think of it?
- He hasn't said anything yet.
- He was never a big talker, your man.
- He's certainly not a chatterbox.
Leave the big talkers
to the village vipers.
I know what people say
about my Joseph.
They say I'm married to a simpleton.
But I know he's different.
He's a good person.
He may not talk, my Joseph,
but he acts.
- Already?
- Yes. Can you believe it?
- I'm sorry, forgive me.
- No. Don't apologize.
As long as I have my fabrics
and my dresses to make...
And I'm really happy for you.
- Does Joseph know?
- Not yet.
- He'll be happy.
- Yes, I think so.
What are you doing here?
- Goodbye, Auguste.
- Goodbye, Félicienne.
Come on dog.
What are you fretting about?
Philomène is with child.
Congratulations.
Don't.
But Joseph, you should be happy.
You'll even get a bonus
from the post office.
It's not that.
I don't know what to do
with children.
Philomène will resent that.
No, she won't, don't worry.
Anyway, it's not a man's job
to look after the children.
Go on, go home.
I'll take breaks. Longer breaks.
That's what I'll do, take breaks.
I'll take breaks.
Cheval!
It's a girl.
Don't you want me
to make you something else?
Turnips? Carrots?
- You eat the same thing every day.
- It's good for the heart.
You'll get ill.
Are you hungry?
Yes.
Yes. Give me a smile.
Give me a smile.
Go on, a smile.
My princess.
Come here.
We're nice and comfy.
Philomène!
I've just finished the dress.
Come up.
If you'd try it on,
it'll help me with the trimmings.
I'll be back.
What are you doing?
She...
She was crying.
She's pretty, isn't she?
Why did you bring this rock home?
It almost killed you.
I'm warning you, this will sting.
Joseph!
- What is he doing?
- I don't know.
He says "you'll see, you'll see",
but I still can't see.
It will be...
It will be beautiful.
I'm building it for you.
Are you listening, Alice?
Every day, I picture it.
For years.
The branches, the trees
and the birds instruct me.
Everyone will visit it.
It will be your palace.
A palace?
- And when will you do that?
- In the evenings. At night.
- After my rounds.
- It's ridiculous.
You're not a mason.
It will all collapse.
I know how to make bread.
Mixing lime with water
can't be any more complicated.
You're crazy.
You'll lead us to our deaths.
What'll we eat? Stones?
- Stop this, Joseph. Stop!
- No, I won't stop.
I'm going to make a palace.
That's what I'm going to do.
We will find solutions for the rest.
End of story.
I don't want my daughter's father
to die of cold.
Dad.
Cheval.
Dad...
- What is that animal?
- An elephant.
I've never seen any elephants here.
Could you bring me one
from your rounds? To show me.
No. I can't bring you one.
You know that here, we use horses
to farm the land.
But there, in Asia, look,
they use elephants.
Because they are strong.
They are hard workers.
That's why I'm putting one here.
But it's big.
Lucky there aren't any here,
they'd break my palace.
- No, they are kind animals.
- I don't want elephants here!
Mom, if you see an elephant,
make it leave!
The secret is patience.
Straight ahead, horsey.
Dad.
Come on. Horsey.
Come on, Dad.
No.
Come on.
Catch me, Dad.
One, two, three.
Sit. Sit down.
Dad! Hey, Dad.
Hello, father.
I'm going to live in Paris.
I've got a position
with a distinguished tailor.
A good position is important.
- What's your name?
- Alice.
Pleased to meet you, little sister.
I'll come back to see you.
- Well, look who's here.
- Taking a stroll in the village?
- Hello, princess.
- How's the madman's palace?
- My father's not mad.
- The madman's palace.
The madman's palace.
The sultan was a good hunter.
He could kill a rabbit
from over 200 m away,
using only his blowgun.
Then, his falcon flew off
to bring him his prey.
Then...
one evening, as he observed the stars
in the middle of the desert,
he heard...
He heard...
The sultana!
It's always the sultana.
I know your story by heart.
I'm not a little girl anymore.
You're annoying.
Because of you,
the whole village teases me!
- Do you see that star, there?
- Yes.
The very white one. It's Sirius.
It is radiant. It's you.
And over there,
do you see those two?
Yes.
That's Philomène and I,
watching over you.
Sirius is the brightest star
in the whole sky.
What about the boy who came
that time, my big brother?
Isn't he there?
Yes, of course. He is...
He's a bit further away.
See? He's there.
Yes.
- Can you see it?
- Yes.
You know,
sometimes,
we don't all live together.
I know.
He lives in another region.
Paris.
- Dad?
- Yes.
Even if people in the village
tease me...
I am very happy
with the palace you're building me.
It's the best palace in the world.
Look, you place your needle
under the loop.
- That's it.
- Yes.
Joseph!
Dad.
Joseph?
Can you hear me?
Joseph.
Two cm closer
and it was your spine, Joseph.
It's a miracle.
And for Alice's cough, rest,
and if possible,
some fat in the soup, for strength.
Most importantly,
you must wrap up warm, miss.
You're wheezing.
It's a damp winter this year.
You must take care.
Right.
Thank you, Philomène.
Philomène,
he must stop this madness.
It's wearing him out.
Do you tell him that?
He only listens to himself.
Now, you two listen to me.
Stay inside, in the warm.
I don't want to see you outside!
Sorry.
- Hello.
- Hello, little one.
Miss.
- Hello.
- Are you from the village?
- Yes, why?
Do you know Postman Cheval?
I've heard he's building
a strange castle.
I'm a journalist from Romans.
I've come to visit it.
Really?
- Can you take me there?
- If you want. It's this way.
- Does he work alone?
- Yes.
How many hours per day?
His postal rounds take about 10 hours,
then, he works here for 10 hours.
- What long days.
- He thinks it's dragging on.
This winter he was bedridden
for one month because of an accident.
What is a journalist?
I must write an article about him
for the Romans Gazette.
- This construction is splendid.
- Do you think so?
- It's the best I've seen.
- Even in Romans?
- Even in Valence.
- People around here think he's mad.
Of course, they're uneducated.
They don't understand.
I know.
But you seem smart.
That's normal, my father,
is Joseph Ferdinand Cheval.
Miss Cheval?
What an honor!
- Why didn't you say so before?
- I prefer to be discreet.
Dad!
I've never been to Romans.
Will you take me there?
Please.
A journalist came.
He wanted to see you.
I showed him around the garden
and he wrote an article about you.
- Did you know?
- No.
- Won't you read it?
- It's not the first.
- Really?
- So I'm told.
So, will you take me to Romans?
Yes, we'll go to Romans.
Cyrille?
I'm coming.
It's with emotion
that we're gathered here, today,
to pay homage to Postman Cheval,
for 30 years of loyal service
to the post office.
In total, that's...
Excuse me,
I think there's a small error.
- No.
- Yes, because...
It's correct, I assure you.
So, in total, that is... 222,720 km
travelled along the paths
of Hauterives and Tersanne,
which makes 32 km per day,
or five times around the world.
Without leaving the Drôme.
I am proud to award you
the post office Medal of Honor.
So, Cheval,
what about this building?
I hope to see it before I leave,
it's partly why I came.
You're famous in the region,
you're a hero.
- How long have you worked on it?
- 13 years.
13 years?
What is it?
A grotto? A sheepfold?
No, it's...
Go on, say it.
A palace.
- A palace.
- A palace?
Where did you get your inspiration?
No, I mean to build it,
how do you do it?
You're a postman, not a mason.
From the fount of creation,
I draw my inspiration.
That's quite impressive.
Is it true?
The trees, the wind and the birds
encourage me.
Really?
Us locals are strong.
All that you see, passersby,
is the work of a peasant
How is Alice today?
- Her cough is severe, very severe.
- And Philomène?
She is...
She is with her. I must go.
Wait, Cheval.
Come here.
You need these more than me.
She's just gone to sleep.
Her temperature?
- We had to use leeches.
- I said no leeches!
Joseph, we had to.
Earlier,
I thought I was going to lose her.
I'm going to get some wood.
Stay with Alice,
she needs your strength.
You will get better, Alice.
Don't leave me on my own.
One evening,
he was observing the stars
and he heard...
The...
Yes,
the sultana.
The sultana who danced
all night long
and who...
who made people happy.
Who made the wind hot
and who made the sun...
bright.
What do you mean no? Is it a joke?
Do you want to kill me again?
I'm sorry. Prefectural order.
It's out of my hands.
Prefectural order... my ass!
Alice will be buried
wherever I decide.
And I decide
that it'll be in my palace!
I feel your pain, Joseph,
but they won't let you.
Can you imagine?
An exhumation?
- A what?
- They would forcibly dig up the body.
I will gather my family
wherever I like.
Wherever I like.
My sincere condolences, father.
These are your granddaughters.
Eugénie.
And...
little...
Alice.
We should go home.
You want to die, Cheval, is that it?
Don't worry,
if you carry on this way, soon
the Grim Reaper will take you to Alice.
That's what you want, isn't it?
Tell her that I love her
more and more.
Tell her that life here is unbearable
and that the house is empty.
You'll tell her?
Tell her my body is broken
and I can no longer breathe.
Alright?
And tell her that Cyrille
named his daughter after her.
Did you see Alice?
She looks like our Alice
at the same age.
That same determined look.
That's from your side.
Have you noticed...
the grotto has collapsed
since you stopped working?
Alice loved hiding in it so much.
I'm going to get some wood.
I must finish it.
You are...
Impressive.
Where did you learn
those architectural techniques?
Excuse-me. Let me introduce myself,
Joseph Cadier.
I've just returned to the region
after a little trip.
Where were you?
In New York for a while, then Boston,
Sweden, Russia...
I've been away for 25 years.
- I've heard about you.
- Me too.
As soon as I arrived,
my curiosity brought me straight here.
Everyone speaks about your work.
How do you get such curved shapes
to hold at that height?
I used a metal framework.
Who gave you that idea?
I gave it some thought.
We will live
at my grandfather's house.
- Hauterives needs a good tailor.
- That's true.
Do you think it will make him happy?
Dreyfus is a puppet.
An anonymous letter,
it's a bit feeble, isn't it?
But the wretch is reserved,
taciturn, unpopular.
An ideal culprit.
I know the type.
Joseph!
Cyrille and his family are coming
to live in Hauterives and...
he's opening a workshop.
Isn't that good news?
I finished my training,
and I thought that you'd...
That people always need
a good tailor.
Oh yes! Elegance,
that's a real art, too.
Perhaps.
Well done for your training.
It's basalt.
The statues stand up
to three meters high.
- They are called "Moai".
- Easter Island.
On the East facade.
They would guard the entrance. No?
I'll think about it.
I'll be off.
I've another 28 km to go.
- I have 3,000 km.
- What?
I'm going travelling again.
I'm not alone.
Alice, look.
Not alone.
Alice!
Look!
Have you seen
how well it's progressing?
I've built three new vaults.
The fairies from the east
will befriend those of the west.
Princess Daoud whispered
that in my ear, while I was sleeping.
Do you like it, Alice?
Alice...
There, Cadier.
Do you like it?
To achieve your goal
you must be stubborn
Can I help you?
Have you been waiting for long?
A while.
Pass me the trowel.
The small one.
This one?
No, both of them.
It's called a "cat's tongue".
You can come and help me.
But don't come to bother me.
"It was around 10 pm,
"when, alerted by the cries
of Marguerite Steinheil,
"the chief of staff found the
President of the Republic, Félix Faure,
"exceptionally virile,
agonizing on the couch,
"dressed in a simple flannel vest.
"Next to him, his mistress, in tears,
was hurriedly getting dressed."
Rich men's mistresses
always cry in the end.
Joseph...
Hello, young man.
Why do I find him
too sharply dressed?
Hello, father.
Let me introduce my friend,
Louis Charvat.
Louis, my father
and his wife, Philomène.
And that's Garance.
Louis wants to photograph
your palace
and to make illustrated
postcards of the photos.
Postcards?
Explain it to us.
My camera obscura
can take five photographs per day.
With the help of a printer,
we could make 100 postcards.
If we sell them for five centimes,
we could quickly make up to 100 francs.
That's a tidy sum.
And your palace could be seen
all over the world.
So, what do you say?
Are there any onions left?
He's happy.
It lacks life.
My palace lacks life?
No, I mean... it might be better
with a figure in front.
On the staircase or the terraces.
Go on.
Never.
Cyrille,
you go.
Go on, Cyrille.
Yes, that's much better.
And one...
And two...
You annoy me, you old grouch.
Go on, you're dying to.
And three...
Don't move.
Ready...
Perfect.
Alice.
Alice!
Where is Alice?
- Where is your daughter?
- Girls?
Your palace is amazing, grandfather.
When I meet my prince charming,
I'll marry him here.
That's nice, darling. Come.
The Story of the Ideal Palace.
It's...
It's your son.
I didn't have time to tell him.
He waited for so long.
Joseph.
- Have you nearly finished your palace?
- Not yet.
I'll know when I've reached the end.
I'm not there yet.
The man over there
wants to offer you a drink.
He's come from Nice,
just to see your palace.
How old are you, now?
44 years old, Mr. Cheval.
I see.
A glass of water.
I'm thirsty.
- Nice.
- What?
Nothing.
The other day,
a gentleman came from Milan.
And I received a letter
from an American.
- Enjoy your visit.
- Thank you.
War has been declared!
The Germans are invading Lorraine!
Do you think I'm going to die?
Yes.
I think so.
You made me happy.
I wasn't made for this world.
I wouldn't have survived it without you.
You found me.
You gave me confidence.
You gave me Alice.
You even picked me up
when I wanted to die.
This palace,
Philomène,
is also yours.
Philomène...
What do you think about
as you walk?
See you tomorrow,
Postman Cheval.
These are your granddaughters.
Eugénie,
and... little Alice.
Mom, if you see an elephant,
make it go away!
Dad. Hey, Dad.
Tell her that I love her a bit more
every day, won't you?
You'll tell her?
I'm very happy
with the palace you're building me.
It's the best palace in the world.
- What on earth is he doing?
- He's lost his mind again.
Apparently he is building
a tomb for his daughter.
Grandfather?
My granddaughter.
Grandfather, this is Eugène.
Sir, I'm very honored to meet you.
We are going to get married.
Will you come to the wedding?
With your prince charming.
Will you come?
What time will it be?
33 years, 9 thousand days,
65 thousand hours for my Palace.
8 years for the tomb.
Work completed, September 22, 1923.
Hello, Félicienne.
Have you finished, Cheval?
What will you do now, Cheval?
Join them.
Here, Cheval, a flower for you.
Look what I found
when I cleared the house.
It was father's.
Your son.
Dad, come and dance.
I'm coming.
Joseph Ferdinand Cheval
died in 1924, at the age of 88.
He devoted 33 years of his life
to building the "Ideal Palace",
which represents
93,000 hours of work.
On November 9,1968,
André Malraux, Minister of Culture,
declared Postman Cheval's
Ideal Palace an historic monument,
"we are lucky to have the only
naive architecture in the world."
Revised and Synchronized by
FAST TITLES MEDIA